Guide to the Richard Wright Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1933-1977; Series I; 38; (92 boxes)
  - ARTICLES, ESSAYS AND REPORTS
    - Scrapbook of Daily Worker articles, 1937 Jun-Dec
      - "James W. Ford Celebrates 44th Birthday - Leads Progressives in Harlem Community" [byline: Richard Wright], Dec 23
      - "Santa Claus Has a Hard Time Finding Way to Harlem Slums" [byline: Richard Wright], Dec 26
      - "Negro, Who Escaped Lynch Mob in South, Ordered to Return by Harlem Relief Officials", Dec 27
    - "The Shame of Chicago," drafts, typescript, corrected, 1951 Dec (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - "Sleeping and Waking," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - [Solution to World Race Problems], draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - "Spanish Snapshots," draft, typescript carbon [related to Pagan Spain ], [1954-55] (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - "A Summation of Ideas in 'Impressions of Asian and African Nationalism'," drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - "There are Still Men Left," draft, typescript, corrected, [1941?] (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - "There is Always Another Café," drafts, typescript and carbon, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - "Things I Never Knew About Negroes Before," drafts, holograph, typescript, corrected and carbon [with notes] (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - "Towards the Conquest of Ourselves," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - "Urban Misery in an American City: Juvenile Delinquency in Harlem"
      - Background clipping, 1944 Nov 26 (Box 7, Folder 149)
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, [1945-46] (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - "What Are Men to You?," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - "What Do I Think of the Theater?"
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, [1941] (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - Published version [as "Theatrical Folk Seem Queer to the Author of Native Son"], World-Telegram, 1941 Mar 22
    - "What You Don't Know Won't Hurt You"
      - Early version, draft, typescript carbon, [ca. 1937] (Box 7, Folder 153)
      - Later version, drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected and carbon, [1942]
    - "Where Do We Go From Here?," draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - "Why the Eyes of the People Turn to the Ring For the Title Bout at Yankee Stadium Tonight," printed version, Daily Worker, 1938 Jun 22 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - [William Faulkner], draft, typescript carbon [first page lacking], 1950 Nov 28 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - "The World Needs a Conscience," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - "A World View of the American Negro," draft, typescript, corrected, [1946] (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - "Writing From the Left," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION
    - Notes, 1938, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 160)
    - Sketch drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1938-40 (Box 8, Folder 161)
    - Sketch, typescript, corrected, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 162)
    - Sketch, typescript carbon, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 163)
    - Curriculum vitae notes, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - BLURBS, FOREWORDS, INTRODUCTIONS, LINER NOTES AND PREFACES
    - Blurb for Abrahams, Peter, The Path of Thunder, draft, typescript, corrected, [1948] (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Blurb for Brooks, Gwendolyn, A Street in Bronzeville, draft, typescript, [1945] (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Blurb for Buckmaster, Henrietta, Let My People Go, book jacket, [1941] (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Blurb for Carter, Hodding, The Winds of Fear
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected [includes draft of letter from Wright to Philip Wylie], [1944?] (Box 8, Folder 168)
      - Printed version, advertisement, [1944?]
    - Blurb for Hayes, Dorsha, Who Walk the Earth
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript (Box 8, Folder 169)
      - Printed version, n.d.
    - Blurb for Kossa, Ethol, Count Me Among the Living, drafts, holograph and typescript (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Blurb for Oswald, Marianne, One Small Voice
      - Drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, [1945] (Box 8, Folder 171)
      - Poster advertisement for French translation, quoting Wright, [1945?]
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1924
      - Clippings - reviews and profiles of Oswald, 1945-47 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Blurb for Replansky, Naomi, Poems, drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - Blurb for Schulberg, Budd, What Makes Sammy Run?, excerpt quoted in review of book, Washington Post, 1941 Apr 13 (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Blurb for Seid, Ruth, Wasteland [by Jo Sinclair], drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, with clipping, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Blurb for Soupault, Phillipe, Age of Assassins, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - Blurb for Stein, Gertrude, Brewsie and Willie
      - Drafts for book jacket (titled "A Steinian Catechism"), holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, [1946] (Box 8, Folder 177)
      - Printed version (titled "A Gertrude Stein catechism"), photocopy, [1946]
    - Blurb for Tolson, Melvin, Dark Symphony, drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Blurb for Unruh, Fritz von, The End is Not Yet, drafts, typescript, corrected (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Foreword to Illinois Labor Notes, No. 4 [National Negro Congress Issue], draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Foreword to Oliver, Paul, Blues Fell This Morning, drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Foreword to Schappes, Morris, Letters From the Tombs
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, [1941] (Box 8, Folder 182)
      - Clippings - Announcement and review, 1942
    - Introduction to Algren, Nelson, Never Come Morning
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, [1942] (Box 8, Folder 183)
      - Printed versions, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 184)
      - Clippings - reviews and advertisements, 1942-51
        [Includes clippings about French translation]
    - Introduction to Drake, St. Clair and Horace Roscoe Cayton, Black Metropolis
      See also: Addresses, etc., Box 2, folder 2
      - for First edition, drafts, typescript, corrected [with notes], [1945] (Box 8, Folder 185)
      - for First edition, setting typescript, corrected and carbon, [1945] (Box 8, Folder 186)
      - Clippings - reviews, 1945-70 (Box 8, Folder 187)
      - for Second edition, draft, typescript (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Introduction to Goodman, Randolph G., "Fire and Cloud" [radio play adaptation of Wright's story]
      See: Writings of Others, Box 89, folder 1084
    - Introduction to Gourdon, Françoise, Tant Qu'il Y Aura La Peur
      - Drafts, typescript and carbon, [1960] (Box 8, Folder 189)
      - Printed version, [1960]
    - Introduction to Lamming, George, In the Castle of My Skin
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, [1953] (Box 8, Folder 190)
      - Clippings - reviews, 1953 Nov 1
    - Introduction to Lest We Forget... [comp. Whit Burnett], drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1955 Jul (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Introduction to Le Musée Vivant issue on "La Culture Nègre," "Richard Wright Présente Le Musée Vivant," clippings - announcements, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Introduction to Nutt, Howard, Special Laughter
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, [1940] (Box 8, Folder 193)
      - Clippings - reviews and advertisement, 1941
    - Introduction to Padmore, George, Pan-Africanism or Communism, drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1956 Mar 2 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Introduction to Sapin, Louis, Papa Bon Dieu titled "Un pièce qui aurait ravi Voltaire...," draft, typescript carbon, [1958] (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Introductory note to Sartre, Jean-Paul, The Respectful Prostitute
      See also: Other Writings - "Reactions to the script of 'La Putain Respectueuse'" Box 88, folder 1081
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, [1948] (Box 8, Folder 196)
      - Clippings - film version, 1951 Aug
    - Liner notes for Barney, Luc, "Les rois du caf'conc'" titled "The Past is Still With Us...," draft, typescript and carbon (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Liner notes for Broonzy, Big Bill, [untitled] - "So Long, Big Bill Broonzy," typescript and carbon, [1958?] (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Liner notes for Jordan, Louis, [untitled], titled "It's Louis Jordan All the Way...," drafts, typescript and carbon (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Liner notes for "Precious Memories"[?], holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Preface to Howe, Russell Warren, The Negro American, drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1956 Mar 9 (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - BOOKS
    - American Hunger
      See: Black Boy, Box 9, folder 202
    - Black Boy
      [drafts of the work published under this title comprised a longer work known by the working title "American Hunger", a part of which was published as such in 1977 from the original galleys]
      - Earliest drafts [titled: "Black Confession"], [1942?], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 202-208)
      - Early drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 10, Folder 209-210)
      - Intermediate drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 10, Folder 211-213)
      - Later drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 214-215)
      - Later drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 216)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 217-219)
      - Setting typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 220-221)
      - Setting typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 222)
      - Chapter XIV drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 12, Folder 223)
      - Organizational notes, typescript and holograph, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 224)
      - Synopsis, setting typescript, corrected and page proof, 1944 Nov 1 (Box 12, Folder 225)
      - Galley proofs, 1944 Apr (Box 12, Folder 226-227)
      - Galley proofs (including author's corrections), 1944 Apr-Jul (Box 13, Folder 228-229)
      - Plate proofs (including revised title pages changed to Black Boy dated Sep 21 1944)
        See: Oversize, Box 124, folder 1970
      - "Comment on American Hunger by Richard Wright" by Dorothy Canfield, typescript carbon, 1944 Jun 8 (Box 13, Folder 230)
      - Copy proof for front of book jacket, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 231)
      - Book jacket proofs [American and German], 1944, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 232)
      - "Don't Wear Your 'Sunday Best' Every Day" [statement encouraging purchase of War Bonds - published on jacket of Black Boy ] drafts, typescript, corrected, [1944] (Box 13, Folder 233)
      - Photographs of book display at Washington Square Library (3 prints), [1945] (Box 13, Folder 234)
      - Clippings
        - Publicity, 1944-47 (Box 13, Folder 235)
        - Announcements, 1944-45 (Box 13, Folder 236)
        - Advertisements, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 237)
          See also: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1925
        - Reviews, 1944-70 (Box 14, Folder 238-241)
        - Best Seller lists, 1945-46
          See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1925
        - Letters to the Editor, 1945-46 (Box 14, Folder 242)
        - General mentions, 1945-69 (Box 14, Folder 243)
        - "Black Boy: A Negro writes a bitter autobiography," photoessay in Life by George Karger [with Italian translation of article for Il Politecnico, 1945 Jun 4
          See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1926
        - Commentary by Sen. Bilbo in Congressional Record, 1945 Jun (Box 14, Folder 244)
      - Fan mail, 1945-58 (Box 14, Folder 245-251)
      - Fan mail, 1945-58 (Box 15, Folder 252-255)
      - Review from radio program by Henry Seidel Canby, script, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 256)
      - Reviews by "Books Across the Sea Society" member, typescript with cover letter, 1945 Sep 6 (Box 15, Folder 257)
      - Adaptation for Coronet magazine, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 258)
      - Radio script adaptation by Robert Rosenthal, "New World A'Coming"
        - Draft, mimeograph, 1946 Apr 30 (Box 15, Folder 259)
        - Review, 1946 May 1 (Box 15, Folder 260)
      - Screen treatment by Tony Petrina, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 261)
      - "Black Boy and Reading," interview statement on background of Black Boy, drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, [1944?] (Box 15, Folder 262)
      - Comment on an excerpt from Black Boy, draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 263)
      - "Black Boy: A Value Analysis" by Ralph K. White, offprint [autographed], 1947 Oct (Box 15, Folder 264)
      - French translation ( Jeunesse Noire )
        - Adaptation for Gavroche, 1946 Sep-Oct (Box 15, Folder 265)
        - Serialization in Les Temps Modernes, (parts I & II), 1947 (Box 15, Folder 266)
        - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 267)
        - Announcements for book signing party, 1948 Jan 24 (Box 15, Folder 268)
        - Announcements and reviews - clippings, 1947-65 (Box 15, Folder 268a)
          See also: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1927
        - "Fiche de lecture" from the Peuple et Culture Club de Lecture, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 269)
      - Book jacket for Italian translation, Ragazzo Negro, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1927
      - Reviews of German, Italian, Spanish and Swedish translations - clippings, 1944-50 (Box 15, Folder 270)
      - Excerpt, "Ich war ein Negerjunge" in Der Neue Zeitung, printed version, 1946 Jan 14 (Box 15, Folder 271)
      - Power of attorney for Mexican translation, draft, typescript (Box 15, Folder 272)
      - Introduction to an excerpt from Black Boy published in 105 greatest authors present the world's best stories, humor, drama, biographies, history, essays and poetry, drafts, typescript, corrected, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 273)
      - American Hunger (1977)
        - Setting copy, with original corrections (1944), photocopy, with afterword by Michel Fabre, typescript, corrected, 1944, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 274)
        - Setting copy, with original corrections (1944) and later typesetting corrections (1977), photocopy, with afterword by Michel Fabre, typescript photocopy, corrected (with further typesetting corrections), 1944, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 275)
          [Donated by Harper & Row, Inc.]
        - Bound galley proof, uncorrected, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 276)
        - Galley proof master set - First pass, corrected, 1977 Jan 7 (Box 16, Folder 277)
          Includes letter from Nahom Waxman to Charles Davis 1980 Mar 28
        - Galley proof master set - Third pass, corrected, 1977 Feb 14 (Box 16, Folder 278)
        - Reproduction proofs, corrected, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 279)
        - Photograph of draft page (p.424) reproduced in book [negative], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 280)
        - Reviews and printed excerpt compiled by curator, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 281)
    - Black Hope
      - Background research material - clippings and printed material, 1937-43
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1928
      - "Old version"
        - Incomplete draft, holograph and typescript, [1940?] (Box 17, Folder 282-283)
          [Includes photocopy of letter from Richard Wright to Paul R. Reynolds, 1940 Feb 6]
        - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 284-289)
        - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 290-292)
        - Intermediate draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 293-298)
        - Intermediate draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 299-301)
        - Intermediate draft, carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 302-309)
        - Intermediate draft, carbon, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 310-311)
        - Developmental fragments for late draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 312-313)
        - Late draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 314-319)
        - Late draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 320-322)
      - "New version"
        - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 323)
        - Early draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 324)
        - Late draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 325-326)
        - Late draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 327)
      - Excerpt
        - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 21, Folder 328)
      - Synopsis
        - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 21, Folder 329)
      - Introduction to a reading, typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 330)
      - Notes and interviews (Box 21, Folder 331-332)
      - Notes and interviews (Box 22, Folder 333-335)
      - Clippings - announcements, 1941-42 (Box 22, Folder 336)
    - Black Power
      - Background material - pamphlets and clipping, 1952-53 (Box 22, Folder 337)
        See also: Series IV, Boxes 132-135, folders 1983-1999
      - Documents and letters prepared for trip to Africa, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 338)
      - Clippings about Wright's visit to Accra (from Accra newspaper), 1953 Jun (Box 22, Folder 339)
      - Travel journal, typescript, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 340-347)
      - Photographs taken by Wright during trip to Ghana, [1953]
        - Boats, men and the sea [39 prints] (Box 23, Folder 348)
        - Buildings [20 prints] (Box 23, Folder 349)
        - Chiefs and rulers [26 prints] (Box 23, Folder 350)
        - Children [72 prints] (Box 23, Folder 351)
        - City life [70 prints] (Box 23, Folder 352)
        - Crowds of people [39 prints] (Box 23, Folder 353)
        - Drums and drummers [12 prints] (Box 23, Folder 354)
        - Forest work [6 prints] (Box 23, Folder 355)
        - Landscapes [14 prints] (Box 23, Folder 356)
        - Marketplace [38 prints] (Box 23, Folder 357)
        - Men [28 prints] (Box 23, Folder 358)
        - Objects [8 prints] (Box 23, Folder 359)
        - Pictures of posters and a business card (George Padmore) [3 prints] (Box 24, Folder 360)
        - Political rally and speaker [27 prints] (Box 24, Folder 361)
        - Sacrificial goat [4 prints] (Box 24, Folder 362)
        - School boys [5 prints] (Box 24, Folder 363)
        - School house [3 prints] (Box 24, Folder 364)
        - Village life [91 prints] (Box 24, Folder 365)
        - Women [71 prints] (Box 24, Folder 366)
        - Women with children [17 prints] (Box 24, Folder 367)
        - Miscellaneous subjects [7 prints] (Box 24, Folder 368)
        - See: Box 141, folders 2038-46 (Box 24, Folder 369-70)
      - Early working draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 371-376)
      - Intermediate working draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 377)
      - Intermediate working draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 378-379)
      - Intermediate working draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 380-385)
      - Late working draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 386)
      - Late working draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 387-393)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 394-396)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 397-399)
      - Setting typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 400)
      - Conclusion
        - Drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 28, Folder 401)
        - Version prepared for United Asia, typescript, 1955 Mar (Box 28, Folder 402)
      - Introduction ["A Propos Possessions"], drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 28, Folder 403)
      - Book jacket [United Kingdom edition], [1956] (Box 28, Folder 404)
      - Clippings
        - Announcements, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 405)
        - Advertisements, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 406)
        - Reviews, 1945-57 (Box 28, Folder 407)
          See also: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1929
        - Commentary on the Gold Coast by Jane Rouch, 1954-55 (Box 28, Folder 408)
      - " Black Power: An Examination by K.A.B.J-Q [K.A.B. Jones-Quartey (Soas)]," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 409)
      - Fan Mail, 1955-59 (Box 28, Folder 410)
      - German translation [ Schwarze Macht ]
        - Clippings - reviews, 1956-66 (Box 28, Folder 411)
        - Reviews from radio programs, scripts, 1956-58 (Box 28, Folder 412)
        - Printed excerpts, 1962, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 413)
        - Notes for literature study group, 1962 Jan 9 (Box 28, Folder 414)
      - Clippings about French, Italian and Swedish translations, 1955, 1957
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1929
      - Comment on Puissance Noire by Sadji Abdoulaye, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 415)
    - The Color Curtain
      - Background and follow-up clippings, 1955-58 (Box 29, Folder 416)
        See also: Series IV, Boxes 135-136, folder 2000-2007
      - Travel Diary
        - Typescript, corrected, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 417)
        - Typescript carbon, corrected, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 418)
      - Business cards from attendees of Bandung conference (with messages), [1955] (Box 29, Folder 418a)
      - Photographs taken by Wright at Bandung conference [44 negatives, 23 contact prints], [1955] (Box 29, Folder 419)
      - Developmental draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 420)
      - Early working draft, typecript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 421)
      - Intermediate draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 422)
      - Intermediate draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 423)
      - Late draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 424-425)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 426)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 427)
      - Galley proof, corrected, 1955 Nov (Box 30, Folder 428)
      - Page proofs, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 429-431)
      - Advance uncorrected proof, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 432)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 433)
      - Questionnaire for Jakarta Afro-Asian Conference, drafts, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 434)
      - Foreword by Gunnar Myrdal, drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1956 Sep 18 (Box 31, Folder 435)
      - Autobiographical statement for book jacket, typescript carbon, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 436)
      - Book jacket, 1956
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1930
      - Clippings
        - Advertisements, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 437)
        - Announcements and reviews, 1955-58, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 438-440)
          See also: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1930
      - Notice from unidentified source [fragment], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 441)
      - U.S.I.A. Press release, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 442)
        [Includes letter from U.S.I.A. to World Publishing Co., 1956 Apr 23
      - Library catalog card, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 443)
      - Reviews of Dutch, French and German translations, 1956-58, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1930a
    - Eight Men
      - "The Man Who Was Almost A Man"
        - Early version, drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, 1935, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 444)
        - Late version, drafts, typescript and carbon (Box 31, Folder 445)
      - "The Man Who Lived Underground"
        - Short version, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 446)
      - "Big Black Good Man"
        - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon, [1957?] (Box 31, Folder 447)
      - "The Man Who Saw the Flood"
        - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, [1937?], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 448)
      - "Man of All Work"
        - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 32, Folder 449-450)
      - "Man, God Ain't Like That..."
        - Drafts, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 32, Folder 451-453)
      - "The Man Who Killed A Shadow"
        - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 454)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 455)
      - "The Man Who Went to Chicago"
        - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 32, Folder 456-457)
      - Complete text
        - Galley proof, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 458)
        - Notes and queries (Box 33, Folder 459)
        - Blurb, draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 460)
      - Book jacket, [1961] (Box 33, Folder 461)